export const BUSINESSMANAGEMENTA2013 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. The ownership right in a limited liability company is in the form of",
A: "commission.",
B: "interest.",
C: "profit,",
D: "shares.",
answer: "D. shares",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. Management embarking on an activity aimed at identifying prospective buyers for their products is known as",
A: "advertising.",
B: "branding.",
C: "market research.",
D: "sales promotion.",
answer: "C. market research",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. Which of the following functions is performed by the central bank?",
A: "Giving advances to customers",
B: "Accepting deposits from the public",
C: "A lender of last resort",
D: "Safeguarding valuables for customers",
answer: "C. lender of last resort",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. The price paid by one party for the promise made by another party in a contract is",
A: "consideration.",
B: "acceptance.",
C: "invitation to treat.",
D: "offer.",
answer: "A. consideration",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. The stage in a product life cycle at which it is launched is",
A: "introduction.",
B: "growth.",
C: "maturity.",
D: "decline.",
answer: "A. introduction",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. An industrial action involving employees working and carefully observing rules is",
A: "boycott.",
B: "lock-out.",
C: "picketing.",
D: "work-to-rule.",
answer: "D. work-to-rule.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. When an employer fails to follow the correct procedures in laying off an employee, that employee is said to be",
A: "redeployed.",
B: "redundant,",
C: "wrongfully dismissed.",
D: "unfairly dismissed.",
answer: "D. unfairly dismissed.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. Which of the following cannot be insured against?",
A: "Employee dishonesty",
B: "Product liability",
C: "Employer’s liability",
D: "Management incompetence",
answer: "D. Management incompetence",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Which of the following sources of revenue is taxable?",
A: "Grants",
B: "Profits",
C: "Subsidies",
D: "Transfers",
answer: "B. Profits",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. Who is referred to as the payee of a cheque?",
A: "The person receiving money from the bank",
B: "The banker who issued the cheque book",
C: "The banker who verifies the cheque",
D: "The cashier who pays the cheque",
answer: "A. The person receiving money from the bank",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. The department in an organization which is responsible for the health and safety needs of workers is",
A: "personnel department.",
B: "finance department.",
C: "legal department.",
D: "marketing department.",
answer: "A. personnel department",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. Market segmentation requires that each segment of the market should be seen as",
A: "cluster.",
B: "continuous.",
C: "heterogeneous.",
D: "homogeneous.",
answer: "D. homogeneous.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. The management process ends with",
A: "planning.",
B: "organizing.",
C: "directing.",
D: "controlling.",
answer: "C. directing.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. Which of the following business units has the governmental regulations and reporting requirements?",
A: "Sole proprietorship",
B: "Company",
C: "Co-operative society",
D: "Partnership",
answer: "B. Company",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. Directives and job instructions are examples of",
A: "downward communication.",
B: "informal communication.",
C: "horizontal communication.",
D: "upward communication.",
answer: "A. downward communication",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. The choice of an appropriate span of control in an organization is not affected by",
A: "competitors.",
B: "efficiency of staff.",
C: "nature of work.",
D: "interdependence.",
answer: "A. competitors",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. Most businesses start operation as a result of ideas about product initiated by",
A: "a broker.",
B: "an entrepreneur.",
C: "a franchisee.",
D: "an employee.",
answer: "B. an entrepreneur",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. A firm’s investment in assets such as cash, debtors and inventory is called",
A: "profit.",
B: "fixed capital,",
C: "working capital.",
D: "liability.",
answer: "C. working capital",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. The lump sum of money paid by the insurer to the insured for prematurely terminating a life policy is",
A: "surrender value.",
B: "salvage value.",
C: "sum assured.",
D: "annuity.",
answer: "A. surrender value",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. Which of the following is the third step in solving a problem in the production department?",
A: "Establishment of objectives",
B: "Gathering of information",
C: "Developing possible alternative courses of action",
D: "Revision of decision to meet dynamic changes",
answer: "C. Developing possible alternative courses of action",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. Which of the following is a secondary stakeholder to a business?",
A: "Customer",
B: "Employees",
C: "Government",
D: "Shareholders",
answer: "C. Government",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. Application of computers in business include all of the following except",
A: "downloading of hardware.",
B: "recruitment and selection.",
C: "billing of customers.",
D: "payroll preparation.",
answer: "B. recruitment and selection",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. Alpha engaged Kofi as an agent for the purchase of a volvo saloon car. Kofi in this case is acting as",
A: "del credere agent.",
B: "general agent.",
C: "special agent.",
D: "universal agent.",
answer: "C. special agent.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. In the sale of specific goods, where the seller is required to put the goods in deliverable state, the title of ownership will pass",
A: "when the goods are put in deliverable state.",
B: "at the time of the contract.",
C: "when the buyer receives notice of the goods in deliverable state,",
D: "when the goods are placed in the seller’s warehouse.",
answer: "C. when the buyer receiver notices of the goods in deliverable state",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. Which of the following agents has the authority to take legal possession of goods if his principal fails to pay his commission?",
A: "Broker",
B: "Del Credere",
C: "Estate",
D: "Factor",
answer: "B. Del Credere",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. A person who wants to buy shares on the stock exchange would first contact",
A: "analyst.",
B: "broker.",
C: "factor.",
D: "shareholder.",
answer: "B. broker.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. Which of the following affects the purchasing power of money?",
A: "Cash ratio",
B: "Optimum employment",
C: "Inflation",
D: "Savings",
answer: "C. Inflation",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. Insurance policy which covers an event that is bound to occur is",
A: "accident.",
B: "life.",
C: "marine.",
D: "motor.",
answer: "B. life.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. Which of the following investors of a company first receive payment in period of liquidation?",
A: "Ordinary shareholders",
B: "Non-preference shareholders",
C: "Debenture holders",
D: "Cumulative preference shareholders",
answer: "C. Debenture holder",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. The insurance premium on employees’ compensation policy is paid by",
A: "government.",
B: "trade union.",
C: "employees.",
D: "employer.",
answer: "D. employer.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. The process by which a business sells the amount owed by its debtors to another company is",
A: "trade credit.",
B: "factoring.",
C: "leasing.",
D: "mortgaging.",
answer: "B. factoring.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. The principle of proximate cause in insurance implies that the event insured against",
A: "is likely to occur.",
B: "is measurable and sure.",
C: "must be the immediate cause of the loss.",
D: "must be the remote cause of the loss.",
answer: "C. must be the immediate cause of the loss",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. The situation whereby labour and management meet to discuss and agree on wages and conditions of service is",
A: "grievance resolution.",
B: "trade union agitation.",
C: "collective bargaining.",
D: "joint consultation.",
answer: "C. collective bargaining",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. In a situation, where A by his actions makes B to believe that C is A’s agent and C contracts with B, C becomes an agent by",
A: "agreement.",
B: "estoppel.",
C: "implication.",
D: "necessity.",
answer: "B. estoppel.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. The payment made for debt factoring is called",
A: "advance.",
B: "commission.",
C: "rent.",
D: "salary.",
answer: "B. commission",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. Pay-As-You-Earn tax is an example of",
A: "regressive tax.",
B: "poll tax.",
C: "sales tax.",
D: "progressive tax.",
answer: "D. progressive tax.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. Oral communication does not include",
A: "face-to-face.",
B: "facsimile.",
C: "meetings.",
D: "seminars.",
answer: "B. facsimile.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. All the following are advantages of advertising except",
A: "persuading people to buy what they do not want.",
B: "increasing the firm’s share of the market.",
C: "educating the public about the uses of goods.",
D: "creating good image for the organization.",
answer: "A. persuading people to buy what they do not want.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. Which of the following documents is a bill of exchange?",
A: "Standing order",
B: "Cheque",
C: "Bill of lading",
D: "Direct debit",
answer: "B. Cheque",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. A bank overdraft is normally granted to",
A: "savings account holders.",
B: "call account holders.",
C: "fixed deposit account holders.",
D: "current account holders.",
answer: "D. current account holders.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. Which of the following is the final stage in the development of a new product?",
A: "Development of prototype",
B: "Test marketing",
C: "Business analysis",
D: "Commercialization",
answer: "D. Commercialization",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. The process by which raw materials are converted into finished goods is known as",
A: "commercialization.",
B: "construction.",
C: "manufacturing.",
D: "warehousing.",
answer: "C. manufacturing.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. In the discharge of a contract where a greater part of the work is done, a claim can be made on the basis of",
A: "quantum meruit.",
B: "damages.",
C: "specific performance.",
D: "agreement.",
answer: "A. quantum merit.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. Which of the following belongs to the extractive industry?",
A: "Road construction",
B: "Taxi driving",
C: "Mending of shoes",
D: "Drilling of crude oil",
answer: "D. Drilling of crude oil",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. An actuary is the expert who",
A: "calculates premium payable for an insurable policy.",
B: "writes up insurance cover notes for the insured.",
C: "assesses the extent of risk sustained by the insured.",
D: "brings clients to an insurance company.",
answer: "A. calculates premium payable for an insurable policy.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. Staffing as a management activity falls under the",
A: "planning function.",
B: "organizing function.",
C: "directing function.",
D: "controlling function.",
answer: "A. planning function",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. The appointment of the board of directors of a bank is carried out by the",
A: "creditors.",
B: "debenture holders.",
C: "promoters,",
D: "shareholders.",
answer: "D. shareholders.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. Re-exporting of imported goods is called",
A: "counter trade.",
B: "entrepôt trade.",
C: "trade liberalization.",
D: "free trade.",
answer: "B. entrepot trade",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. Which of the following functions is not performed by a wholesaler?",
A: "Hawking",
B: "Publicity",
C: "Re-packaging",
D: "Warehousing",
answer: "A. Hawking",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. The situation whereby a holder of a bill receives an amount less than the face value before the maturity date is",
A: "retiring a bill",
B: "redeeming a bill",
C: "discounting a bill",
D: "dishonouring a bill",
answer: "C. discounting a bill",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},


]